ANDREW CLARK

Senior Chemical Engineer

SUMMARY

Senior Chemical Engineer with over 20 years of experience in the pharmaceutical industry, with a proven record of outstanding leadership and project management skills. Experience managing multiple projects simultaneously including successful delivery of critical project milestones under time constraints.

EXPERIENCE

Chemical Engineer

2015 - Ongoing

Dufour

Los Angeles, CA

- Maintained daily performance checks for all machinery, ensuring optimum 24hour performance at all times
- Training of more than 20 people in quality related themes
- Plant troubleshooting and optimization (DMC+, Spyro, Aspen one, Aspen Hysys)

Chemical Engineer

2013 - 2015

Drouin S.A.R.L.

Pittsburg, PA

- Certification of ISO 9001, ISO 14001 and OHSAS 18000 standards
- Initiated quality assurance plan, GlobalGAP v.4 certified
- Raised the production by 2 tons on daily basis by research and process modification
- Managed 5 science and engineering interns

Junior Chemical Engineer

2011 - 2013

Blanchette

Los Angeles, CA

- HAZOP, SIL, safety risk assessment, analysis and management
- Produced purified water that met the increasingly strict requirements for industrial use
- Applied lean, Kaizen & fundamental engineering principles to processes resulting in savings over \$500k

EDUCATION

BSc in Chemical Engineering

2006 - 2010

University of Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

GPA 3.85 / 4



LANGUAGES

English Native

German Proficient

SKILLS

Programs

MathLab · Simulink · ChemCAD ·

AutoCAD

Safety Standards

ANSI · PHA · LOLA